Hi. I'm Sanjana
嗨，我是Sanjana Reddy，我在谷歌的高级
解决方案实验室担任机器学习工程师。
Reddy, a machine learning engineer at Google's Advanced Solutions Lab.
There's been a lot of excitement around generative AI and all the new
最近，生成式AI以及相关的新的技术，包括即将出现
的新的顶点AI特性，如Gen AI Studio, Model
Garden, Gen AI API等，引起了大量的关注和热议。
such as Gen AI Studio, Model Garden, Gen AI API.
Our objective in this short session is to give you a solid footing
在这个简短的课程中，我们的目标是让你对构成所
有Gen AI神奇的基本概念有一个扎实的理解。
all the Gen AI magic possible.
Today I'm going to talk about transformer
今天，我将要谈论的是Transformer模型和BERT模型。
models and the BERT model.
The recent breakthroughs in the past ten years include the usage
过去十年的最新突破包括使用神经网络来表示文本，
of neural networks to represent text,
such as Word2vec an N-grams in 2013.
例如2013年的Word2vec和N-grams。
In 2014, the development of sequence to sequence models
2014年，序列到序列模型的发展，
such as RNN's and LSTM’s
如RNN和LSTM，
helped improve the performance of ML models on NLP tasks
帮助提高了机器学习模型在自然语言处理任务上的性能，
such as translation and text classification.
如翻译和文本分类。
In 2015, the excitement came with attention mechanisms
2015年，随着注意力机制的出现及其基于该机制建立的模
型，如Transformer和Bert模型，引起了人们的关注。
as Transformers and the Bert model.
In this presentation we'll focus on Transformers.
在这个课程中，我们将重点讨论Transformer。
named Attention As All You Need.
Although all the models before Transformers were able to represent words
尽管Transformer之前的所有模型都能将单词表示为向量，
as vectors, these vectors did not contain the context
但这些向量并不包含上下文，
and the usage of words changes based on the context.
而单词的使用会根据上下文而变化。
For example, bank and river bank
例如，"bank"和"river bank"与"bank robber"中的
"bank"在注意力机制出现之前可能具有相同的向量表示。
versus bank in bank robber might have the same vector
representation before attention mechanisms came about.
A transformer is an encoder decoder model
Transformer是一个使用注意力机制的编码解码模型。
that uses the attention mechanism.
It can take advantage of pluralization
它可以利用复数化和同时处理大量数据，因为它的模型
架构，注意力机制有助于提高机器翻译应用的性能。
and also process a large amount of data at the same time.
because of its model architecture,
attention mechanism helps improve
the performance of machine translation applications.
Transformer models were built using
Transformer模型是使用注意力机制为核心构建的。
attention mechanisms at the core.
A transformer model consists
一个Transformer模型包括编码器和解码器。
of encoder and decoder.
The encoder encodes the input sequence and passes it to the decoder
编码器对输入序列进行编码，并将其传递给解
码器，解码器解码表示以用于相关任务。
and the decoder decodes the representation for a relevant task.
The encoding
编码组件是一个由相同数量的编码器堆叠而成的栈。
The research paper that introduced Transformers
引入Transformer的研究论文将六个编码器堆叠在一起。
stack six encoders on top of each other.
Six is not a magical number.
六并不是一个神奇的数字，它只是一个超参数（Hyperparameter）。
It's just a hyperparameter.
The encoders are all identical in structure, but with different weights.
这些编码器在结构上都是相同的，但权重不同。
The first layer is called self attention.
第一层称为自注意力。
The input of the encode are first flows through a self attention layer,
编码器的输入首先流经一个自注意力层，这有助于编码或查
看单词的相关部分，因为它编码输入句子中的中心词。
which helps to encode or look at relevant parts of the words
as it encodes a central word in the input sentence.
And the second layer is called a feedforward layer.
第二层被称为前馈层。
The output of the self attention layer is
自注意力层的输出被送入前馈神经网络。
fed to the feedforward neural network.
The exact same feedforward neural network is independently applied
相同的前馈神经网络独立应用于每个位置。
The decoder has both the
解码器既有自注意力层，也有前馈层，但在它们之间是编码器
解码器注意力层，帮助解码器关注输入句子的相关部分。
self attention and the feedforward layer,
but between them is the encoder decoder, attention layer
that helps a decoder focus on relevant
parts of the input sentence.
After embedding the words in the input sequence,
在对输入序列中的单词进行嵌入（Embedding）
后，每个嵌入向量都会流经编码器的两层。
each of the embedding vector flows through the two layers of the encoder.
the exact same network with each vector flowing through it separately.
Dependencies exist between these paths
在这个自注意力层中，这些路径之间存在依赖关系。
However, the feedforward layer does not have these dependencies
然而，前馈层没有这些依赖关系，因此各种路
径可以在它们流经前馈层时并行执行。
while they flow through the feedforward layer.
In the self attention layer, the input embedding is
在自注意力层，输入嵌入被分解成查询向量、键向量和值向量。
broken up into query, key, and value vectors.
These vectors are computed using weights
这些向量是通过Transformer在训练过程中学到的权重计算的。
that the transformer learns during the training process.
All of these computations happen in parallel
所有这些计算都是在模型中以矩阵计算的形式并行进行的。
in the model, in the form of matrix computation.
Once we have the query key
一旦我们有了查询键和值向量，下一步就是将每个
值向量乘以"Softmax"分数，以便将它们加起来。
and value vectors, the next step is to multiply each value
vector by the soft max score in preparation to sum them up.
The intention here is to keep intact the values of the words
这里的目的是保持你想要关注的单词的值不变，并通过将它
们乘以很小的数字（例如0.001）来排除不相关的单词。
you want to focus on and leave out a irrelevant words
by multiplying them by tiny numbers
like 0.001, for example.
Next, we have to sum up the weighted value vectors
接下来，我们需要对加权值向量求和，从而
得到这个位置的自注意力层的输出。
which produces the output of the self attention layer at this position.
to the feedforward neural network.
To sum up this process of getting
总结一下这个过程，我们采取以下步骤来获得最终的嵌入。
the final embeddings, these are the steps that we take.
We start with the natural language sentence
我们从自然语言句子开始，嵌入句子中的每个单词。
embed each word in the sentence.
After that, we perform multi-headed
然后，我们在这种情况下执行8次多头注意力，并
将这个嵌入的单词与相应的加权矩阵相乘。
attention eight times in this case and multiply
this embedded word with the respective weighted matrices.
We then calculate the attention using the resulting Q K.V.
我们首先使用结果Q K.V矩阵计算注意力。
Finally, we can concatenate the matrices to produce the output matrix,
which is the same dimension as the final matrix
that this layer initially got.
现在有多种Transformer的变体。
Some use both the encoder and the decoder component from the original architecture.
有些只使用编码器，有些只使用解码器。
Some use only the encoder and some use only the decoder.
A popular encoder only architecture is Bert.
一个流行的只有编码器架构是Bert。
Bert is one of the trained transformer models.
Bert是一种训练过的Transformer模型。
Bert stands for bidirectional encoder representations
Bert代表双向编码器表示，来自Transformer，由谷歌于2018年开发。
Since then,
从那时起，已经建立了多种Bert的变体。
multiple variations of Bert have been built.
Today, Bert Powers Google Search.
如今，Bert为谷歌搜索提供动力。
You can see how different
你可以看到Bert为同一搜索查询提供的结果有多么不同。
Before and after,
在此之前和之后，Bert分为两种变体进行训练。
Bert was trained in two variations.
One model contains Bert Base,
一个模型包含Bert Base，它有12个
Transformer的堆栈，大约有1.1亿个参数，
which had 12 stock of Transformers
with about 340 million parameters.
The Bert model is powerful because it can handle long input context.
Bert模型之所以强大，是因为它可以处理长输入上下文。
It was trained on the entire Wikipedia corpus and books corpus.
它在整个维基百科语料库和书籍语料库上进行了训练。
The Bert model was trained for 1 million steps.
Bert模型经过了100万步的训练。
Bert is trained on different tasks,
Bert在不同任务上进行了训练，这意味着它具有多任务目标。
which means it has multi-task objective.
This makes Bert very powerful
这使得Bert非常强大，因为它接受了各种任务的训练。
because of the kind of tasks it was trained on.
It works at both a sentence level and at a token level.
它既可以在句子级别上工作，也可以在Token级别上工作。
These are the two
这是最初发布的两个不同版本的Bert。
different versions of Bert that were originally released.
One is Bert Base, which had 12 layers,
一个是Bert Base，它有12层，而Bert Large有24层。
whereas Bert Large had 24 layers.
And compared to the original transformer, which had six layers.
与原始的Transformer相比，它只有六层。
The way that Bert works is that it was trained on two different tasks.
Bert的工作方式是在两个不同的任务上进行训练。
Task one is called a masked language model, where the sentences are masked
任务一称为掩码语言模型，其中句子被掩
盖，模型被训练来预测被掩盖的单词。
and the model is trained to predict the masked words.
If you were to train Bert from scratch, you would have to mask
如果要从头开始训练Bert，你将不得不
掩盖语料库中的一定百分比的单词。
a certain percentage of the words in your corpus.
The recommended percentage for masking is 15%.
建议的掩盖百分比是15%。
The masking percentage achieves a balance
掩盖百分比实现了过少和过多掩盖之间的平衡。
between too little and too much masking.
Too little masking makes the training process extremely expensive,
太少的遮罩使训练过程非常昂贵，太多
的遮罩则去除了模型所需的上下文。
and too much masking removes the context of the model requires.
The second task is to predict the next sentence.
第二个任务是预测下一句话。
For example, the model is given two sets of sentences.
例如，模型给出了两组句子。
Bert aims to learn the relationships between sentences
Bert的目标是学习句子之间的关系，并根据第一句预测下一句。
and predict the next sentence given the first one.
For example,
例如，句子A可能是一个人去了商店，句子B是他买了一加仑牛奶。
sentence A could be a man went to the store
and sentence B is he bought a gallon of milk.
Bert is responsible for classifying if sentence
Bert负责分类句子B是否在句子A之后的下一句。
B is in next sentence after sentence A.
This is a binary classification task.
这是一个二分类任务。
This helps Bert perform at a sentence level in order to train Bert.
这帮助Bert在句子级别上表现良好，为了训练Bert，
You need to feed three different kinds of embeddings
你需要为输入句子向模型提供三种不同类型的嵌入，
to the model for the input sentence.
You get three different embeddings token
分别是Token嵌入、段落嵌入和位置嵌入。
segment and position embeddings.
The token embeddings is a representation
Token嵌入是输入句子中每个Token的表示。
of each token as an embedding in the input sentence.
The words are transformed into vector
单词被转换为特定维度的向量表示。
Bert can solve NLP tasks
Bert可以解决涉及文本分类的自然语言处理任务。
that involve tex classification as well.
An example is to classify whether two sentences say
一个例子是，对于两句话“我的狗很可爱”和“他喜欢玩
耍”，我们需要分类这两句话在语义上是否相似。
my dog is cute and he likes playing are semantically similar.
The pairs of input texts are simply concatenated and fed into the model.
将输入文本对简单地连接起来并输入模型。
How does Bert distinguish the input in a given pair?
那么Bert如何区分给定对中的输入呢？
There is a special token represented by SEP
有一个由SEP表示的特殊标记，用于分隔句子的两个不同部分。
that separates the two different splits of the sentence.
Another problem is to
另一个问题是学习句子中单词的顺序。
As you know, Bert consists of a stack of transformers.
众所周知，Bert由一堆Transformer组成。
Bert is designed to process input sequences up to a length of 512.
Bert设计用于处理最长为512的输入序列。
The order of the input sequence is incorporated into the position embeddings.
输入序列的顺序被整合到位置嵌入中。
This allows Bert to learn a vector representation for each position.
这使得Bert能够为每个位置学习一个向量表示。
Bert can be used for different downstream tasks.
Bert可用于不同的下游任务。
Although Bert was trained on mass language modeling
尽管Bert是在大规模语言建模和单句分类上进行训练的，但它可以用
于流行的NLP任务，如单句分类、句子对分类、问答和单句标记任务。
and single sentence classification, it can be used
for popular NLP tasks like single sentence classification.
Sentence Pair Classification.
Question Answering and single sentence tagging tasks.
Thank you for listening.
感谢你的聆听。